MARIO CAMPOPIANO

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CONTACT ME

Mobile: 615-582-5551



mcampopiano92@gmail.com



https://github.com/mcampopiano



https://www.linkedin.com/in/mcampopiano/

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML5
- CSS3, Bootstrap
- · JavaScript, React.js
- JSON Server
- Git/GitHub
- SQI
- SQLITE
- Python
- Django

PROJECTS

Budget

Budget is an app for people who want to take advantage of the envelope budgeting system bud don't want to use cash. With it users can create different "envelopes" for each spending category (e.g., groceries, restaurants, movies), set a monthly budget for it, and log purchases for each month.

A dashboard view allows users to visualize at a glance their total budget, total spent, remaining budget amount, and net total for the month.

- · Full Stack Application
- Front-end Created using React.js
- REST API created with Python/Django
- Implements full CRUD functionality
- UI styled with CSS3

Front end repo:

https://github.com/mcampopiano/budget-react

Backend repo:

https://github.com/mcampopiano/budget-python

Publish Or Perish (POP)

Publish Or Perish is an application for short story writers to help keep track of their stories and, most importantly, their submissions. As a writer myself, this was a tool I had long desired but had not found anything like it on the market, so I decided to build it.

Users are able to quickly see information about publication magazines, track their own submissions to said magazines, and record notes for their specific writing projects.

- Created using React.js
- Implements full CRUD functionality
- UI styled with CSS3

https://github.com/mcampopiano/publish-or-<u>perish</u>

ABOUT ME

Shortly after getting married my wife and I sat down and talked about how we wanted to keep track of our spending, and decided to look for a budget app. At the time no app existed with the features we wanted, so we decided to try our hand at making our own.

Ultimately we ended up creating a spreadsheet with google that did the trick for us, but I never stopped thinking about what it would take to get into tech.

Eventually, I decided to attend Nashville Software School. I love studying languages; before beginning my journey into the tech field I spent time as a foreign language instructor, and I have absolutely loved learning new programming languages. I look forward to being in a field where continual learning will give me the opportunity to always grow and challenge myself.

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE APPRENCTICE SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Nashville Software School Sep 2020 - Mar 2021

Intensive full-time 6-month software development bootcamp anchoring learning with both individual and team-based projects. Tech Stack: Python/ Django; React.js; Javascript; HTML5; CSS3; SQL fundamentals.

In addition to the syntax involved with the various programming languages:

- Practiced the process of planning for a project, including wireframing, creating a dependency graph, Entity Relationship Diagram, and detailed tickets for features
- Used and git and GitHub for version control for individual and group projects. This flow included: creating and cloning repositories, pushing/pulling to and from the local repository, checking out branches for features, making commits, and resolving merge conflicts with Main branch as they arose.
- Gained firsthand experience developing web applications both as part of a team and as an individual.
- Participated in SCRUM framework for accomplishing group projects.





mcampopiano92@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mcampopiano/

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

FREELANCE ENGLISH AS A SECOND LANGUAGE INSTRUCTOR (Italy)

02/2019 - 06/2020

Worked as a private language instructor, with an emphasis on teaching not only the syntax but the process of learning a new language.

TECNOTILES, INC 07/2017-01/2019

OPERERATIONS MANAGER

TecnoTiles was an Italian owned tile processing company which receives large sheets of tile from customers then cuts them down to the desired dimensions. The company was sold in January 2019 and is now called ExactaTiles.

Job duties included:

- Managing and tracking daily operations through an excel program
- · Assisting in the management of warehouse staff
- Translating between Italian and English as necessary

SIMMONS BANK

01/2016-10/2016, 01/2017-07/2017

CONSUMER LENDING SPECIALIST

- Processed Real Estate Loan applications as part of a collaborative team
- · Worked on a strict deadline basis
- After seeing that the many different steps of the process could be broken down into distinct sections of work, suggested that the department move to an assembly line type working style where teams specialized in specific parts of the process
- Once this assembly line model was adopted, the department saw more success both in meeting deadlines and customer satisfaction

BOOKS-A-MILLION

08/2015-12/2015, 10/2016-12/2016

Co-Manager

PEYRON-RE UMBERTO I SCUOLA COMPRENSIVO (Italy)

01/2015-07/2015

English Language Instructor

In January began a three-month contract as a teaching assistant, which was extended to six-months.

TIMESHARE ADVOCACY INTERNATIONAL

01/2014-12/2014

Credit Department Head

TAI was company which helped clients who felt they had been misled into buying a timeshare cancel their contracts. Implemented a system of daily building out a task list of what could reasonably be accomplished within a day if we pushed ourselves, and within three months of steady working the department was caught up on all backlogs. The company was sold in January of 2015.

Job duties included:

- Overseeing the work of the department, including the interviewing and hiring of staff
- Working directly with clients and the three main credit reporting agencies to clear delinquencies on timeshare payments incurred as part of the cancellation process

US BANK 02/2012-12/2013

Assistant Branch Manager

Hired as a personal banker, subsequently promoted to senior banker and then assistant manager.

SunTrust Bank 03/2011-02/2012

Financial Services Representative

Hired as a teller and subsequently promoted to a Financial Services Representative

EDUCATION

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Intensive Full stack Development bootcamp

International TEFL Academy

Received a Teaching English as a Foreign Language Certificate

MIDDLE TENNESSEE STATE UNIVERSITY

2014-2016: Global Studies